♪ pulsing my senses weak ♪
Critical hit.
He couldn't have gone far.
He wouldn't go
to a hospital.
♪ now time has run its course ♪
♪ there is no other way ♪
The bleeder works for Kirk.
He'll know where to find them.
I have a location.
I was trying to help.
He has to know that.
I'm not on your side here,
Kate.
♪ pulsing my senses weak ♪
♪ I was hunting,
I went running ♪
♪ now time has run its course ♪
♪ there is no other way ♪
I need to speak
with the patient.
He's gone.
As you well know,
one of the keys to my success
is a clear and consistent
understanding
of my own limitations.
So often people
overestimate themselves,
misapply their gifts.
The cleaner suddenly
fancies herself the strategist.
Wisdom is
learning the boundaries
of one's designated lane.
For instance,
this, I will do poorly.
Clumsily,
with more mess than necessary.
It'll take longer
and be considerably
more unpleasant to boot.
But I can't very well
have you do it, can I?
Raymond Reddington,
my favorite rubio.
Ay carajo, I haven't seen you
since you snuck off at Carnival.
Red, Jesus.
What's wrong with you?
We're looking for a name.
Take a close look, Manny.
He worked for a man who abducted
someone I care about.
He's a cop.
Who's his rabbi?
I don't know,
but I know who might.
- Is it true? She's alive?
- Apparently.
Wait, wait.
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
How is that... there were
complications during labor.
And the doctor,
he declared her dead.
He lied.
But there was a funeral.
I-I was a pallbearer.
Yes, and who knows
what was in that casket?
It was a charade, Aram.
So Agent Keen is alive?
Uh, but her funeral
and her death...
She faked her death.
Why would she do that?
To get away from Reddington.
So that her and Tom and Agnes
could have a normal life.
Away from us?
Yes, after everything
we did for her.
Best we could tell,
Liz and Tom's plan
was to go into hiding in Cuba.
Alexander Kirk found them.
Why? What does he want
with Agent Keen?
Look, all we know right now
is that
when Reddington got there,
Liz and Tom were gone.
I just got off the phone
with the embassy in Havana.
Briefed them on Kirk, gave them
the tail number to his plane.
If that was how he was planning
to get off the island,
- that's not gonna happen.
- And, uh, what about Agnes?
At this point, we don't know.
Notify FBI headquarters.
Elizabeth Keen is alive.
The plane is ready.
Mato and the baby?
Not yet.
Notify me
as soon as they're here.
My baby.
- She's on her way.
- That's what you said before.
- Masha--
- My name is Elizabeth.
I understand that you have
questions, that you're upset.
I'm sorry it has to be
like this.
- You're not my father.
- Well, I am, Masha. I am.
And I intend
to prove that to you.
Agnes will be brought here,
but the person doing that has
a job to do first.
What job? With Tom?
What are you doing to Tom?
Let me out!
_
Oh.
There's nothing more depressing
than a failed Communist state.
It doesn't even really pay
to be corrupt.
When dirty cops
play poker in America,
they're able to play
for real money.
Let's raise the stakes.
_
A new game.
You tell me who the head
worked for,
you keep the money,
a 5-way split.
Oh, we're keeping the money.
A young woman and her child
were taken.
A Russian has entered
the country.
I have it on good authority
your friend here
was assisting him.
I think it's time
for you to leave.
Make that a 4-way split.
_
I'll give you a name.
Well, isn't this
your lucky day?
The head worked for
a Jhosep Balzan?
I've never heard of him.
Yeah, he's a supplier
of all manner of contraband
on the island.
If the people you're looking for
are still in Cuba,
Balzan is protecting them.
Should I assemble a team?
Dembe, call Silvio in
San Cristobal.
Tell him to put a team together.
We're going after Elizabeth.
Sync and corrections by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com
Here.
You think I'd drug you?
You kidnapped
my infant daughter,
my husband, and me.
I'd say you're capable
of anything.
Listen...
you were my entire life.
You were all your mother and I
ever cared about.
Now you don't know
any of that
because Reddington took you
away from us
when you were just
a little girl.
He and your mother
had an affair.
For a time, I thought
maybe he was the father,
but I have proof that
he's not.
He's just a spiteful,
evil man.
Couldn't accept it when Katarina
broke off the affair.
One day I came home,
and you were gone.
He'd taken you.
I never thought
I'd ever see you again...
until there you were
in the news,
you... and Reddington,
the most wanted fugitives
in the world.
If you cared so much about me,
you wouldn't hold me hostage.
He'd taken my beautiful child
and turned her into a criminal.
Attack my wedding,
everyone I love.
Everything I did was to get
my child away from Reddington.
Who understands that
more than you?
You did the exact same thing,
faked your own death
to get your child away from him.
We have a problem.
The PNR have surrounded
the plane.
Then find another plane.
Agnes will be here shortly.
And Tom?
_
Shh!
Hey, they have my baby! Please!
Keen, you breathe a word,
I'm gonna fire two bullets--
one in the cop
and the other between the eyes
of that screaming kid.
You got it?
_
He's got a gun!
No, don't-- please!
Where are we on Kirk?
PNR grounded his plane.
There's no sign of him or Keen.
I informed the Bureau
that Elizabeth Keen has risen
from the dead.
They said three Hail Mary's
and they're on the lookout
for the zombie apocalypse.
I understand. You feel played.
Don't you, sir?
Look, we should
be halfway to Havana by now.
Why? She obviously
doesn't want our help.
Maybe or maybe not,
but she needs it.
You're willing to risk your life
after what she did?
All right, let's just have
this conversation.
Keen lied to us,
took advantage of all of us,
and no one is more upset
about that than I.
Or... relieved.
Truth be told, I didn't think
it was possible
to be this joyous and livid
at the same time.
But I have a job to do--
find Keen and her family
and bring them home safely.
And I know that no matter
how I feel, I can do that job.
I need to know if each of you
can say the same.
♪ desde que te fuiste ♪
♪ las cosas no andan mal ♪
♪ pero si quieres volver ♪
♪ con gusto sere tu man ♪
♪ la muchacha se fue ♪
♪ se fue ♪
♪ esa muchacha se fue ♪
♪ se fue, se fue ♪
_
Hello, Raymond.
Elizabeth, are you okay?
Of course she is.
Unlike you, I would never hurt
my own daughter.
Elizabeth?
- Elizabeth.
- I'm on your left.
Constantin.
What do you want? Name it.
You bring her out unharmed,
you'll have it.
Of course, the Concierge
of Crime wants to cut a deal.
You'll give me whatever I want?
Yes.
In exchange for Masha?
Whatever you desire.
What I desire
is to raise my child,
to watch her grow,
and to have back the 26 years
of being a father
that you took from me.
But you can't give me that,
can you?
No, because she was
never yours to raise.
Patrol unit incoming.
Military patrol.
Armored military.
- Agnes. Do you have Agnes?
- I don't have her.
Go. Find Agnes and Tom.
I'm not leaving here
without you.
You just don't get it,
do you, Raymond?
She doesn't want to be with you.
That's why she faked
her own death--
to get away from you.
Raymond, we have to go now.
- If they get you, they'll kill you.
- Raymond.
Did you hear me?
You have to go.
Go!
Elizabeth, I will come for you.
Harold, gather your team.
Reddington. Where are you?
Tell me you have Agent Keen.
No, but she's still
on the island.
Kirk's preparing her exit plan.
I don't know what
the preparations are,
but I know who can find out--
Manuel Esteban.
The Chilean Spymaster?
- Who's Esteban?
- Our next Blacklister.
Manuel Orentez Esteban.
Leader of Pinochet's Caravan of Death
that institutionalized
a state-sponsored
system of terror
through abuse, abduction,
and murder.
According to our database,
he died in 1989.
Except he didn't.
Esteban is alive and well
and a legendary enforcer
for a series of
authoritarian regimes.
Assuming what you say is true
and Esteban is alive,
what makes you think he can
help locate Keen?
Kirk's man in Cuba
is protected by the military.
If the military is involved,
Esteban will know about it.
We'll never find Esteban
in time.
We have no assets in Cuba.
Of course you do, Harold.
Esteban.
He works for your government.
Castro took him in,
and the CIA immediately
put him on the payroll
as a double agent.
What little you know
about the inner workings
of the Cuban government
is courtesy of Manuel Esteban.
The CIA knows where to find him,
and he knows
where to find Elizabeth.
_
What are you talking
to Reddington for?
I thought
your task force was disbanded
after Agent Keen's death.
It turns out she's not dead.
She's been kidnapped.
And if we have any hope
for finding her,
it rests in finding Esteban.
I need to know
where to find him.
I hate getting
into bed with Reddington.
I... hate needing him
and his list.
If you find Agent Keen, will he
continue to give you names?
He just did-- Esteban.
According to him,
Esteban works for the Agency.
Good Lord.
Is there anything that man
doesn't know?
How can we contact him?
The Agency
reaches out to him
through the State Department's
weekly travel advisory.
Set a meeting, a message is
encoded in the advisory,
detailing where and when.
The meeting is set
for the National Museum.
You'll be going to Cuba
undercover, as tourists.
He'll be going. Not me.
You may be fine with doing this
job, no matter how you feel.
- I can't.
- How you feel?
How about how Keen feels?
Forget about what she did
and try to figure out
why she did it.
I have, and someday,
maybe I'll be okay with it.
But right now I'm not.
What?
You're okay with this?
No.
But for now, I accept it.
You'll be going alone.
Here's how it's gonna work.
Your agent will be detailed
with the Dallas/Fort Worth
Arts and Cultural Committee.
Esteban will expect to meet
at the Cafe Aventura
across from
the National Museum.
Once inside, take a table in
the back, order an egg coffee.
I appreciate you
burning a source for this.
You knowing he exists is
the least of Esteban's problems.
Now that we're all chummy
with the Cubanos,
his relationship
with the Agency is, uh,
something of a liability.
You're gonna scrub him?
Let's just say, if you wanna
reach out to Esteban,
you should do it quickly.
Jesus. Hot as balls in here.
You guys actually drink
this stuff?
_
Kill him first.
Come back for the cop.
Meet you at that place.
Aah!
Hey! Get out of the car!
Get out of the car!
Romina.
- Move it.
- Hey.
Hey.
Let her go.
Look, you can take me,
all right?
Do whatever you want.
Just give me my little girl!
Hey! I'm begging you!
Give me my little girl!
Please!
You and I are gonna have
some fun, man.
- Hey.
- Shh.
Don't talk.
They'll kill us.
Where are we?
How many people
does he have down there?
My family.
They have a way out.
He wants me to tell him how.
He's going to kill me.
I've seen his face.
Anyone who sees--
It's him.
Right. Upright.
So the rumors are true.
They sent you to finish me.
Not quite, no.
The Americans want me dead,
so our relationship
dies with me,
so I get embarrassed.
Look, I'm not here
to kill you, pal,
I'm here to tell you that
Raymond Reddington wants
to see you.
Oh, so now the US government
is Reddington's messenger.
Oh, you know how it works.
The American government
has deals
with all kinds of scumbags.
Look, I'll tell you
how it works.
You're gonna give me
your phone.
I'm gonna dial a number.
Okay, cowboy.
I like this one.
Reddington?
Manuel Esteban.
My heavens, you're a devil
to get ahold of.
I'm surprised we've never met.
I'd like to have
a little chitchat.
How would you feel
about a blind date?
I'm looking for a woman.
Aren't we all?
Her name is Elizabeth Keen,
and the man holding her
has the protection of the FAR.
They know where she is, which
means you know where she is,
or you could certainly find out.
Why would I help you?
You're an anarchist.
Probably.
Maybe more
of an opportunist.
And I have the opportunity
to help you.
You spent a lifetime bouncing
from one authoritarian regime
to the next.
But this is the last stop.
You're a relic.
The detente between America
and Cuba
makes you a man without
a country.
Sooner or later,
both sides will want you dead.
My money's on sooner.
I can take care of myself.
Clicking like a hairless
fruit bat is impressive, Manuel,
but you and I both know
avoiding a lamppost
is very different from
avoiding an assassin's bullet.
Echo location can't help you
with that, but I can.
What do you propose?
I know what it's like
to be hunted.
I've protected myself
for 30 years.
And I can protect you...
after you locate
Elizabeth Keen.
All right,
listen to me, please.
The baby-- I can pay you.
- Quiet.
- Not me. I have a friend.
Whatever you want,
he'll help you.
We'll get you off the island,
he'll protect you.
- I said quiet, man.
- Look, just let her go!
All right, you can kill me.
I don't care.
Just let my baby go.
Let's go and dig.
I know you don't want
to talk to me. Fine.
Then listen.
It was excruciating to watch you
mourn Elizabeth's death,
to know that I was
making you endure that.
Yes, I betrayed you,
but only after
you had betrayed her.
Raymond, you have to change.
I took Elizabeth from you,
and now I need your help
to get her back.
But when you do,
as I'm sure you will,
you have to let her go.
Why don't you wait in the car?
I have a location
for the girl.
And the child?
I asked, but people know nothing
about a child.
Tell me about the location.
It is heavily protected.
20, maybe more.
I'll need more men.
That won't be necessary.
I have a blood disorder.
Good.
I'm dying.
Even better.
They're here.
Oh, baby.
Are you okay, sweetheart?
Let me look at you.
Oh, you're okay.
Oh, my God.
It's okay.
You're a strong girl.
Everything's gonna be okay.
You're with Mommy now. Shh.
She's beautiful.
Yes? Yes, it's good to hear from you.
You disappoint me, Balzan.
Yes, yes, of... course.
It's the pilot.
Everything is on schedule.
I'll notify the men.
I assume the husband's
been taken care of.
- Hello?
- Is it done?
_
What's taking so long?
Angel.
Angel?
He wants to talk to you.
Hello. Who's this?
All that matters is that
you have a little girl,
and you have her mother.
Tom.
I'm coming for them,
for you.
And not just me, an army.
You hear me?
An army is coming for you.
You lost Tom.
We'll be going soon.
Where?
Home.
I'm not going anywhere
with you.
I faked my death
to have a normal life.
There's nothing normal about
being held prisoner.
A temporary inconvenience.
You'll see in time that
the normal life you want,
I'm the only one who can
give that to you.
She's hungry,
which means I need to feed her,
which means
you need to leave.
Of course.
I've done what I can,
but you must hurry.
Kirk has chartered
a float plane.
- There isn't much time.
- For either of us.
A stevedore will meet you
on Pier 36.
I've arranged for a berth
on a container ship bound
for Caracas.
Adios.
We have an ETA
on that plane?
Your job here
is done, Donald.
Like hell it is.
I came here to get Keen.
I'm not leaving without her.
You think I'm gonna let you
tag along so you can inform
the people who kidnapped
Elizabeth
they have the right
to remain silent?
I appreciate your assistance,
but I'm not interested in having
an ethical debate with you
about whether they have
the right to consult
with an attorney before I put
a bullet in their head.
Excuse me.
What about that dirtball?
I suppose you think, uh,
I should be okay
with letting him walk.
It's entirely up to you.
You made a deal with him.
Yes, in order
to save Elizabeth,
I made a deal with
the devil of the day.
I did. You didn't.
If you have a problem
with that,
you've got 12 hours
before his ship leaves
to do something about it.
Otherwise,
safe travels home, Donald.
Elizabeth?
Ready to go?
Balzan!
He's gone. Your guards,
your security, they're all gone.
The child and the girl--
find them.
This is Agent Mojtabi.
Aram, it's Tom.
Tom? Hey. Tell me
you're with Agent Keen.
The man who took Agnes--
he's driving a blue Dodge sedan,
late '50s,
He's taking her straight to Liz.
If we can follow the car--
We can find them. Okay,
let me think. Let me think.
Okay, what I'm thinking
is, um,
did you help Agent Keen
fake her death?
Aram!
Not helpful, I know.
Okay. But did you?
At the funeral, when you put
a flower on her casket--
The car--
it has an old tube radio.
- Local oscillator.
- The oscillator. Right. Of course.
Okay, if you could rewire it,
you might be able to turn
the PLL receiver into this--
...into a low power
mono FM transmitter
that produces a signal that you
can trace. Yeah. I know.
You do?
Then, uh, why are you...
To get you to trace
the signal, Aram.
Oh. Oh, you already...
uh...
Wow, that's, uh,
that is impressive.
Okay. Hang on. I'm on it.
- Thank you.
- Did you know?
At the christening,
when you made me a godfather
to Agnes--
Look, man, I know
you're upset, all right?
But right now is not
the time.
I'm trying to ping the signal.
Waiting for a reply...
from both of you.
Aram...
of course I knew.
I'll let you know when, uh,
I find the signal.
Thank you.
Shh, shh, shh.
Shh. Shh.
Please, Agnes, stop crying.
Mommy's here.
Shh, shh, shh.
Think about
what you're doing.
What are you gonna do?
Hurt me?
Hurt my baby?
Kirk will kill you if you do.
Are you a mother?
Do you have children?
Look at her...
Hey!
No!
Little mama,
you got spirit.
Get up. Get the baby.
You'll learn to trust me.
Get the baby and the things.
We're leaving.
Like hell we are.
No!
I wish there was
another way, I do,
- but Reddington's on his way.
- Agnes!
Come on. Get her onboard.
Yeah.
- Mr. Reddington. It's Aram.
- It's not a good time.
I have information
on Agent Keen. A location.
She's being held
near this--
A small fishing port
in Playa Larga.
- We're on our way.
- Oh.
Magic. How'd you do that?
We'll have Elizabeth shortly.
And Agnes.
- Agnes?
- Right. Tom called.
Thanks to him, I was able
to track the vehicle
where he had last seen Agnes,
a blue Dodge sedan.
Thank you, Aram.
Agnes is here.
Luis, you and your men take
the perimeters to the north
and the west.
Dembe, secure the house.
Silvio, you're with me
to the south.
You stay put.
♪ I think you know ♪
♪ what the game is ♪
♪ I hope you've brought ♪
♪ all your players ♪
♪ 'cause this is a war ♪
♪ oh ♪
♪ this is a war ♪
♪ pick up the gun ♪
♪ with his name on ♪
♪ you'll never know ♪
♪ where it came from ♪
♪ this is a war ♪
That's not your child.
♪ ooh ♪
They're gone.
I'm sorry, Raymond.
We have her.
You told them
he worked for us?
Do you have any idea
what kind of blowback
I'm dealing with here?
And it doesn't take long to
find out who told the Cubans.
I heard it was
an anonymous tip.
Agent Ressler...
Are you a traitor
or-- or just a moron?
Look, the Agency was gonna
assassinate Esteban...
I have
no direct knowledge--
...so the Cubans wouldn't
find out
who was feeding secrets
to the CIA.
Whoever this
anonymous source is,
he just saved a lot of lives.
What are you talking about?
Now that America knows about
Esteban's
little torture chamber,
the Cubans are going to want
plausible deniability.
_
Let's not mince words.
You took it upon yourself
to tell the Cubans about our--
No, I took it upon myself
to stop what Esteban was doing.
Do you have any idea
what that was?
No, because all you care about is
what Esteban was doing for you.
There are bigger issues,
Agent Ressler.
Torture, abuse, murder.
I don't see any bigger issues
than that.
Excuse me.
Have you heard
from Reddington?
No.
Uh, last time
I spoke to him,
he was on his way
to the location
where Agent Keen was
being held.
I'm sure he'll call.
I'm sure they're okay.
I think you were wrong
not going to Cuba.
I'm not saying what Agent Keen
did was right,
but as long as her life
is in danger,
as long as Agnes's life
I think we have to put
our feelings aside.
What's happening to Liz
is her own fault.
I know that sounds harsh,
but it's true.
She made decisions
that have consequences,
and now she has to live
with them.
- She's in trouble.
- I know, and I'm angry about that.
because if she'd
behaved differently,
she wouldn't be
in this position.
But she is.
And no matter how we feel,
I think we have to do
something about it.
I don't.
If you don't help,
and something happens
to Agent Keen or Agnes,
I know you.
You won't be able
to live with yourself.
Yes? It's Tom.
Tell him we were too late.
Kirk has Elizabeth.
What about Agnes?
She's with us. Safe.
Your daughter is safe.
Raymond, I've been thinking
about where we go from here--
Sync and corrections by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com